window.__examLoadCallback({
  "title": "Computer_Network - Physical_Layer — Slot 1 (15 Questions)",
  "duration": 42,
  "sections": [
    {
      "name": "Physical_Layer — Slot 1",
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "<p>To send same bit sequence, NRZ encoding require <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2020)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Same clock frequency as Manchester encoding</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Half the clock frequency as Manchester encoding</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Twice the clock frequency as Manchester encoding</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>A clock frequency which depend on number of zeroes and ones in the bit sequence</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>Half the clock frequency as Manchester encoding</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/331403/isro2020-52\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "<p>If there are n devices (nodes) in a network, what is the number of cable links required for a fully connected mesh and a star topology respectively <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2017)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>n(n-1)/2 , n-1</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>n, n-1</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>n-1, n</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>n-1,  n(n-1)/2</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>n(n-1)/2 , n-1</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/128657/isro2017-30\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "<p>In networking terminology UTP means <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2017)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Uniquitous teflon port</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Uniformly terminating port</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Unshielded twisted pair</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Unshielded T-connector port</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>Unshielded twisted pair</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/128646/isro2017-28\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "<p>Physical topology of FDDI is? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2017)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Bus</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Ring</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Star</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>None of the above</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>Ring</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/128644/isro2017-27\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "<p>Bit stuffing refers to <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2016)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>inserting a 0 in user stream to differentiate it with a flag</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>inserting a 0 in flag stream to avoid ambiguity</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>appending a nipple to the flag sequence</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>appending a nipple to the use data stream</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>inserting a 0 in user stream to differentiate it with a flag</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/49497/isro2007-24-isro2016-67\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "<p>How many characters per sec (7 bits + 1 parity) can be transmitted over a 2400 bps line if the transfer is synchronous ( 1 start and 1 stop bit)? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2015)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>300</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>240</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>250</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>275</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>300</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/51713/isro2015-51\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "<p>What frequency range is used for microwave communications, satellite and radar? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2015)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Low frequency: 30 kHz to 300 kHz</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Medium frequency: 300 kHz to 3 MHz</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Super high frequency: 3000 MHz to 30000 MHz</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Extremely high frequency: 30000 kHz</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>Extremely high frequency: 30000 kHz</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/51711/isro2015-49\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "<p>A T-switch is used to <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2015)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Control how messages are passed between computers</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Echo every character that is received</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Transmit characters one at a time</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Rearrange the connections between computing equipments</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>Rearrange the connections between computing equipments</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/51709/isro2015-48\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "<p>Consider a 50 kbps satellite channel with a 500 milliseconds round trip propagation delay. If the sender wants to transmit 1000 bit frames, how much time will it take for the receiver to receive the frame? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2014)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>250 milliseconds</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>20 milliseconds</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>520 milliseconds</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>270 milliseconds</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>270 milliseconds</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/54975/isro2014-45\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "<p>In the Ethernet, which field is actually added at the physical layer and is not part of the frame. <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2013)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Preamble</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>CRC</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Address</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Location</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>Preamble</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/43976/isro-2013-38\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "<p>The voltage ranges for a logic high and a logic low in RS-232 C standard is <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2013)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Low is 0.0 V to 1.8 V,  High is 2.0 V to 5.0 V</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Low is -15.0 V to -3.0 V,  High is 3.0 V to 15.0 V</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Low is 3.0 V to 15.0 V,  High is -3.0 V to -15.0 V</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Low is 2.0 V to 5.0 V,  High is 0.0 V to 1.8 V</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>Low is 3.0 V to 15.0 V,  High is -3.0 V to -15.0 V</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/43973/isro-2013-37\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "<p>IEEE 1394 is related to <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2013)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>RS?232</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>USB</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Firewire</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>PCI</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>Firewire</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/43819/isro-2013-20\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "question": "<p>What is the maximum number of characters (7 bits + parity) that can be transmitted in a second on a 19.2 Kbps line. This asynchronous transmission requires 1 start bit and 1 stop bit. <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2013)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>192</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>240</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>1920</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>1966</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>1920</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/43817/isro-2013-19\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "question": "<p>One SAN switch has 24 ports. All 24 supports 8 Gbps Fiber Channel technology. What is the aggregate bandwidth of that SAN switch? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2011)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>96 Gbps</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>192 Mbps</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>512 Gbps</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>192 Gbps</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>192 Gbps</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/52868/isro2011-71\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 15,
          "question": "<p>Data is transmitted continuously at 2.048 Mbps rate for 10 hours and received 512 bits errors. What is the bit error rate? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2011)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>6.9 e-9</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>6.9 e-6</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>69 e-9</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>4 e-9</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>6.9 e-9</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/52174/isro2011-50\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
});
